# **Chris Harley**

Software Engineer Atlanta, GA | (678) 865-3314

Portfolio | Github | Linkedin | Email

Creative software engineer with a passion for learning and the ability to pick up new languages and technologies as needed. I'm a Veteran with a background in operations. Combined with my military and management experience I bring strong skills in problem solving by using innovative ideas and I work well with a team.

## **Software Development Skills**

 Debugging, JavaScript, Python, Node.js, React, Express, Redux, RESTful API, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, Bootstrap, Flexbox, CSS Grid, AWS, HTML, CSS, ES6, Mongo Db, API, Git, Agile, CRUD Applications, Remote Development

### **Education**

Berklee College of Music | B.A. Music Business | Boston, MA

Dec 2011 - Dec 2015

DigitalCrafts | Certificate in Software Engineering | Atlanta, GA

March 2020 - July 2020

 Software engineering training program covering full-stack development including, but not limited to JavaScript, Python, including an emphasis on cutting-edge frameworks like React/Redux and server-side technologies including Node.js, Express, and PostgreSQL.

## **Software Development Portfolio**

#### soundWav Live Site | Github

June 2020

- Member of a 2-person development team building an full stack recording studio booking application
- Primary responsibility included building a PostgreSQL database allowing users to create an account, and successfully book time in a recording studio
- Built with Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, EJS, Sequelize

## top3 Live Site | Github

May 2020

- Member of a 2-person development team building a travel application that list the top three restaurants, hotels, tours, nightlife and site seeing for the entered location
- Responsibilities included designing and assembling a fully mobile-responsive layout and fetching data from a third party API
- Built with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Triposo API

#### scenelt Live Site | Github

April 2020

- Front end project to view movies and save them to your watch list
- This project use the OMDb movie API
- Built with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, OMDb API

## **Professional Work Experience**

## DevelopATL | Freelance Web Developer | Atlanta, GA

May 2018 - Present

- Design, build and maintain web applications using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Confer with customers to prioritize needs, resolve conflicts and determine solutions
- Maintain understanding of current web technologies through continuing education

#### Luxottica | Distribution Supervisor | Atlanta, GA

July 2017 - March 2018

- · Carried out supervisory responsibilities in accordance with company policy
- Responsible for interviewing, hiring, and training employees
- Developed tracking system that double worked production efficiency

#### Phillips-Van Heusen | Operations Assistant | Atlanta, GA

January 2016 – July 2017

- Monitored associates to ensure timely and quality of production
- Developed organization system to increase department production
- Provided training and guidance to subordinate personnel

#### **Division Operations Training & Planning Manager | U.S Army**

June 2005 – October 2015

- Responsible for all training operations of over 400 personnel
- Ensured all personnel met department of defense training regulations
- Served as liaisons between units and senior officers to ensure mission readiness